<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Our Solar System</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="title_activity_planet_data">PlanetDataActivity</string>
    <string name="title_activity_quiz">Quiz</string>
    <string name="numQuestions">/20</string>
    <string name="quizAgainButton">QUIZ ME AGAIN!</string>
    <string name="planetDataButton">PLANET DATA</string>
    <string-array name="planet_data">

        <item>
The Sun is our nearest star. The Sun provides us with light
            and heat. It gives life to the Earth and the
            Earth would have no life at all without the energy
            it receives from the Sun. Without the Sun, there
            would be no daylight and no oceans of liquid water.\n\n

From Earth, the Sun looks like it moves across the sky
            in the daytime and appears to disappear at night.
            This is because the Earth is spinning towards the east
            as it orbits the Sun.\n\n

This huge ball of superhot gas weighs as much as 330,000 Earths.
            About 1,300,000 Earths would fit inside the Sun!\n\n

Everything in the Solar System orbits or revolves around the Sun.
            The larger an object is, the more gravity it has. Because
            the Sun is so large, its powerful gravity attracts all the
            other objects in the solar system towards it. At the same time,
            these objects, which are moving very rapidly, try to fly away
            from the Sun, outward into the emptiness of outer space. The
            result of the planets trying to fly away, at the same time
            that the Sun’s gravity is trying to pull them inward is that
            they become trapped halfway in between. Balanced between flying
            towards the Sun, and escaping into space, the objects in the
            solar system spend eternity orbiting around their parent star.\n\n.\n\n
        </item>
        <item>Mercury is the smallest and fastest planet in the solar system. It is also the closest planet to the Sun. It is named after the Roman messenger god, Mercury, the fastest Roman god.
            The planet Mercury was known by ancient people thousands of years ago. It has no moons.\n\n
Mercury is the smallest of the eight planets in our solar system. It is only a little bigger than Earth\'s moon. It would take more than 18 Mercurys to be as big as the Earth.\n\n
Mercury orbits the sun once every 88 Earth days, one Mercury year. Although a year is shorter on Mercury than on Earth, a day on Mercury is longer than an Earth day. One Mercury day lasts for 59 Earth days! \n\n
The surface of Mercury looks much like Earth\'s moon. It has a lot of impact craters. Mercury has almost no atmosphere. Because it is so close to the Sun, it can be very hot. On its sunny
            side, Mercury can reach a scorching 800 degrees Fahrenheit! (But Mercury is not the hottest planet in the solar system. The hottest planet is Venus.) \n\n
        </item>
        <item>
       Venus was named after the Roman goddess of love and beauty, and it is considered the brightest planet in Earth\’s nighttime sky. This is because it is nearby and because it is blanketed in highly reflective clouds. \n\n
Venus is the hottest planet. It has a temperature of at least 462 degrees Celsius (864 degrees Fahrenheit), no matter where you go on the planet.
\n\n
Venus has many volcanoes. We do not know for sure, but it is possible that Venus has more volcanoes than any of the other planets in our solar system.\n\n
Venus takes 225 days to orbit the Sun, a Venus year. Venus rotates very slowly, so that a day on Venus lasts more than 100 Earth days. Venus also rotates in the opposite direction as almost all the other planets. Instead of the Sun rising in the east and setting in the west,
            the Sun on Venus would appear to rise in the west and set in the east.\n\n
        </item>
    <item>The Earth is the third planet from the Sun and comes between the planet Venus and the planet Mars. The Earth is the planet where we live. The Earth is different from every other planet in the solar system in a number of ways. It is the only planet that has liquid water on its surface in large quantities. The Earth is the only planet in the solar system that has life, and unlike the other planets, which do not support life, the Earth has a wide diversity.  This has only been possible because of the Earth\’s atmosphere, which has protected the Earth and allowed life to flourish, and the large quantities of water.
The Earth is larger than Mercury, Venus, and Mars, the four of which make up the “inner” planets of the solar system (those planets between the Sun and the Asteroid Belt). The Earth is the only inner planet to have one large satellite, the Moon.  Mars has two very tiny moons. Mercury and Venus have no moons. \n\n
The Earth takes 365 and one-fourth (¼)  days to complete its orbit round the Sun.  The Earth’s year is therefore 365 days long, but the ¼ days are added up and every fourth year, we have one extra day, on the 29th of February.  This fourth year is called a Leap Year (366 days) and is always a year that can be divided exactly by 4 –  for example, the years 2000, 2004, 2008, 2012, and, 2016.\n\n
As the Earth orbits round the Sun, it turns on its axis, rotating completely around in 24 hours.  The side of the Earth that faces the Sun has daytime, and the side of the Earth that is turned away from the Sun has nighttime. \n\n
As the Earth orbits round the Sun it tilts very slightly and this tilt gives us the seasons.  When the Earth has tilted so that the northern half of the Earth is a little away from the Sun, the northern hemisphere (half of the Earth\’s sphere) has winter. At the same time, the southern hemisphere has summer. While it is winter in England, it is summer in Australia, and vice versa. \n\n
The Earth\’s surface is split into plates (called tectonic plates) which float on a rocky mantle – the layer between the surface of the earth, its crust, and its hot liquid core.  The inside of the Earth is active, and earthquakes, volcanoes and mountain building takes place along the boundaries of the tectonic plates. \n\n
As a result of the geology on Earth, the surface of the Earth has far fewer impact craters than the surface of the other “inner” planets. The craters on Earth have sunk down or been worn away by wind and rain over millions of years.  \n\n
</item>
    <item>Mars is the fourth planet from the Sun and the next planet beyond Earth. Mars is about one-sixth the size of Earth. Mars is known as the “Red Planet.” This is because it gets its red color from the iron oxide (like rust) in its soil.\n\n
Mars is named for the Roman god of war. The Greeks called the planet Ares, after their own god of war. The Romans and Greeks both associated the planet with warfare because its color resembles the color of blood.\n\n
Mars has two small moons. Their names are Phobos and Deimos. They are named for the sons of Ares. Phobos means “fear,” and Deimos means “flight.”\n\n
Mar\’s surface is rocky, with canyons, volcanoes, dry lake beds and craters all over it. Red dust covers most of its surface.\n\n
The highest mountain and volcano in the Solar System is on the planet Mars. It is called Olympus Mons and is 16 miles (24 kilometers) high which makes it about three times higher than Mt. Everest.\n\n
Mars has a day that is almost the same as Eath\’s: 24 hours and 40 minutes. However, it takes almost twice as long to orbit the Sun: 687 days, a Martian year.
Mars has a very thin atmosphere, one that is about 100 times less dense than the one on Earth. The Martian atmosphere contains more than 95 percent carbon dioxide, approximately 3 percent nitrogen, and much less than 1 percent oxygen. \n\n
With its atmosphere, Mars has clouds and wind just like Earth. Sometimes the wind blows the red dust of Mars into a dust storm. Tiny dust storms can look like tornados and large ones can be seen from Earth. Mars\’ large storms sometimes cover the whole planet!\n\n
</item>
<item>The Asteroid Belt is a  ring-shaped gathering of objects located
    between the orbits of the planets Mars and Jupiter. It has many
    irregularly shaped bodies. Some of these are asteroids, which give
    the belt its name.\n\n
About half the mass of the belt is contained in its four largest bodies: Ceres,, Vesta,,Pallas, and Hygiea. Ceres is the largest and is classified as a dwarf planet. \n\n
The total mass of the asteroid belt approximately 4% that of the Earth\’s moon. It is suggested that the  matter from the asteroid belt could have become a planet when the solar system was forming; however, the great gravity from Jupiter disrupted the would-be planet\’s formation and caused the
    matter to break apart, instead, into the Asteroid Belt we know today.\n\n
        </item>
<item>
Jupiter is the largest planet in the solar system. Jupiter is so large that all of the other planets in the solar system could fit inside it. More than 1,000 Earths would fit inside Jupiter.\n
\n
Jupiter is the fifth planet from the sun. When viewed from Earth, it is usually the second brightest planet in the sky, after Venus. The planet is named after Jupiter, the king of the Roman gods.\n\n
Jupiter is a giant gas planet. If Jupiter had been about 80 times more massive, it would have become a star rather than a planet. Its atmosphere is made up of mostly hydrogen gas and helium gas, just like the sun. The planet is covered in thick red, brown, yellow, and white clouds.\n
\n
One of the most famous features of Jupiter is the Great Red Spot. This is a giant spinning storm, resembling a hurricane. At its widest point, the storm is about three and a half times the diameter of Earth. Jupiter is a very windy planet. Winds on Jupiter can reach 400 mph!\n
\n
Jupiter has four faint rings. These rings are made up mostly of tiny dust particles.\n
\n
Jupiter rotates, or spins, faster than any other planet. The day on Jupiter is only about 10 hours long. The planet orbit is elliptical, or oval-shaped. It takes just under 12 Earth years for Jupiter to make one revolution around the sun, a Jupiter year..\n
\n
Jupiter has 62 known moons. The four largest moons are Io, Europa, Ganymede, and Callisto.
\n\n
</item>
    <item>
Saturn is the sixth planet in the solar system. Saturn is the last planet that can be seen without using a telescope or binoculars and the planet was known in the ancient world before telescopes were invented. However, the rings of Saturn can only be seen using a telescope. \n\n
Although Jupiter, Saturn, Uranus, and Neptune&#8212;the “outer” solar system planets&#8212;all have some rings, the rings of Saturn are the most extensive of any planet in the Solar System.  They are made up of trillions of particles of rock, dust and ice which all orbit the planet.
\n\n
Saturn has at least 18 moons. The largest of the moons, Titan, is the second largest in the Solar system, after Jupiter\’s moon, Ganymede.  \n\n
Saturn is the second largest planet in the Solar System, after the giant Jupiter. Its mass is 95 times that of the Earth. \n\n
Saturn takes 29 and one-half years to make one complete orbit of the Sun, a Saturn year. \n\n
Like Jupiter, Saturn spins much faster on its axis than the Earth. Saturn, although so much bigger, completes a rotation in just over 10 hours, a Saturn day. \n\n
    </item>
<item>
Uranus is the seventh planet, and lies more than 2,800 million kilometers from the Sun. Each orbit around the Sun lasts 84 Earth years, a Uranus year. However, a day on Uranus is just over seventeen hours long. \n\n
Uranus has 13 known rings, both bright and dark. Like the rings of Saturn, some are made up of black dust and very large rocks. \n\n
Uranus is the third largest planet in our Solar System. Sixty-four Earths would fit inside it. Despite its size, it spins rapidly. Like Venus, Uranus spins in the opposite direction of Earth&#8212;clockwise east to west&#8212;so on Uranus, the sun rises in the west rather than the east.
\n\n
Uranus spins like a top knocked over on its side. This means that the Sun is sometimes directly overhead at the poles. Each pole has a summer and a winter lasting 21 years, making them both the hottest and coldest places on the planet! \n\n
Uranus has 27 known moons. None of these are very big. The largest satellites are Oberon and Titania, which were named after characters in Shakespeare\’s play, A Midsummer Night\'s Dream. \n\n
Uranus has at least a dozen dark, dusty rings. At least one ring is created by meteorites crashing into a small satellite.\n\n
</item>
    <item>Neptune is 57 times bigger than the Earth, but, like Uranus, spins quite rapidly—one day lasts only 16 hours 7 minutes.
        Neptune\’s average distance from the Sun is about 4,500 million kilometers, and one year on Neptune lasts for almost 165 Earth years.  \n\n
Neptune has at least five dark, narrow rings, and 13 known moons. By far the largest
        moon is Triton. Triton was named after the son of the Greek god Poseidon.\n\n
</item>
    <item>Modern telescopes have been able to see hundreds of icy objects beyond the orbit of Neptune, in a region now known as the Kuiper Belt. The objects are probably left over from the birth of the planets in our solar system. They were ejected to this remote outer region by interactions with the planets.\n\n

The Kuiper Belt is named after Gerard Kuiper, a Dutch-born astronomer who suggested in 1951 that some comets we see on Earth may come from this region. The first Kuiper Belt Object was discovered in 1992, proving that Kuiper’s theory was correct. \n\n

Finding objects in the Kuiper Belt is difficult because they are very hard to see and move so slowly. It takes hundreds of years for these objects to complete one orbit around the Sun.\n\n

Most of the objects are small, typically 10-50 kilometers across. Until recently, Pluto, a dwarf planet named after the Greek god of the underworld, was the largest member of the Kuiper Belt, though a number of other objects were almost as large.However, in 2005, an even bigger object then Pluto was found: Eris. \n\n

When discovered, Eris, named after the Greek goddess of chaos, was found to be twice as far as Pluto from the Sun. Eris\’ orbit is also tilted by 44 degrees, so it travels well above and below the paths of the other planets. Eris has a moon, which was named Dysnomia after the daughter of Eris in Greek mythology. Dysnomia means “lawlessness.” \n\n
</item>

        </string-array>

        <string-array name="planet_answers">
            <item>VENUS</item>
            <item>EARTH</item>
            <item>SATURN</item>
            <item>SATURN</item>
            <item>MERCURY</item>
            <item>THE SUN</item>
            <item>VENUS</item>
            <item>EARTH</item>
            <item>MARS</item>
            <item>ASTEROID BELT</item>
            <item>JUPITER</item>
            <item>URANUS</item>
            <item>NEPTUNE</item>
            <item>KUIPER BELT</item>
            <item>NEPTUNE</item>
            <item>MERCURY</item>
            <item>JUPITER</item>
            <item>JUPITER</item>
            <item>PLUTO</item>
            <item>MARS</item>
            <item>MERCURY</item>
            <item>VENUS</item>
            <item>VENUS</item>
            <item>EARTH</item>
            <item>JUPITER</item>
            <item>MARS</item>
            <item>JUPITER</item>
            <item>NEPTUNE</item>
            <item>THE SUN</item>
            <item>MERCURY</item>
            <item>EARTH</item>
            <item>JUPITER</item>
            <item>JUPITER</item>
            <item>JUPITER</item>
            <item>JUPITER</item>
            <item>KUIPER BELT</item>
            <item>VENUS</item>
            <item>EARTH</item>
            <item>MARS</item>
        </string-array>


        <string-array name="planet_questions">
            <item>Which planet is second from the Sun?</item>
            <item>Which planet is third from the Sun?</item>
            <item>Which planet is sixth from the Sun?</item>
            <item>Which planet has the largest system of rings around it?</item>
            <item>Which planet is closest to the Sun?</item>
            <item>What is the name of the star that gives life to the Earth?</item>
            <item>Which planet was named for Roman goddess of love and beauty?</item>
            <item>Which planet is where we live?</item>
            <item>Which planet is named after the Roman god of war?</item>
            <item>What is the band of objects between Mars and Jupiter?</item>
            <item>Which planet has an enormous storm that circles the planet?</item>
            <item>Which planet rotates on its side?</item>
            <item>Which planet is eighth from the Sun?</item>
            <item>Which of these is an area that contains Pluto?</item>
            <item>Which planet was named for the Roman god of the seas?</item>
            <item>Which planet was named for the Roman messenger god?</item>
            <item>Which planet was named for the Roman king of the gods?</item>
            <item>Which planet rotates faster than any other planet in the solar system?</item>
            <item>Which of these is considered a "dwarf" planet?</item>
            <item>Which of these is nicknamed the "Red Planet"?</item>
            <item>Which planet orbits the Sun in only 88 Earth days?</item>
            <item>Which planet has a day that lasts more than 100 Earth days?</item>
            <item>Which planet is brightest in the Earth\'s nighttime sky?</item>
            <item>Which planet takes 365 days to orbit the sun?</item>
            <item>Which planet is fifth from the sun?</item>
            <item>Which planet has a moon whose name means "fear"?</item>
            <item>Which of these is the largest planet in the solar system?</item>
            <item>Which planet has a moon named Triton?</item>
            <item>Everything in the solar system orbits around which of these?</item>
            <item>Which is the smallest (non-dwarf) planet in the Solar System?</item>
            <item>Which of the "inner planets" has the fewest visible impact craters?</item>
            <item>Which planet is typically the second-brightest in the Earth\'s night sky?</item>
            <item>Which planet is so large that all of the other planets could fit inside it?</item>
            <item>Which planet is home to the Great Red Spot?</item>
            <item>Which planet has the shortest day?</item>
            <item>Which of these is an icy region beyond Neptune?</item>
            <item>Which planet is the hottest in the solar system?</item>
            <item>Which is the largest of the "inner" solar system planets?</item>
            <item>Which planet has the highest mountain in the solar system?</item>
        </string-array>

    </resources>

